We can follow this process to fill out all the nodes in our charts.
我们可以根据这个过程 填入表格中的所有节点
&gt;&gt; Now, we need to look for the most likely path.
— 现在我们要寻找最有可能的路径
Each time frame will modify the transition probability times the output
每个时间帧都可以改为转移概率乘以
probability.
输出概率
Note, to the most likely path may not be the greedy path, in other words.
注意 最有可能的路径可以不是贪婪的路径
The highest expected value with each transition,
换句话说 每次转移中最高的期待值
may not necessarily lead to the highest valued overall path.
不必引导到最高值的整体路径
In this case the maximum path since, be this one.
在这个例子中 最高值的路径是这个
&gt;&gt; Okay, so let's consider the transition from time one to time two.
— 那么我们考虑从时间 1 到时间 2 的转移
We can stay in state 1 or move to state 2.
我们可以停留在状态 1 或者移动到状态 2
What should we use to compare the two options?
我们应该使用什么对比这两个选择呢？
&gt;&gt; Expected value of staying in state 1 is 0.8 times 0.5,
— 停留在状态 1 的期望值是 0.8 乘以 0.5
yet going from state 1 to state 2 is 0.2 times 10 to the- 7.
但是从状态 1 转移到状态 2 的期望值是 0.2 乘以 10 的 -7 次方
The greedy algorithm would expect to stay in state 1 since that value is
贪婪算法期望停留在状态 1 因为这个值
bigger.
更大
&gt;&gt; Okay, I see, how does Viterbi account for the overall path?
— 好 我明白了 Viterbi 如何解释总体路径？
&gt;&gt; We need to keep track of the probability of each possible sequence of
— 我们要跟踪网格图每个可能序列的
the trellis.
概率
There are only two nodes in each sequence so far, so
每个序列中只有两个节点
the two probabilities are 1 x 0.5 x 0.8 x 0.5, which is equal to 0.2.
所以两个概率是 1 x 0.5 x 0.8 x 0.5 等于 0.2
&gt;&gt; Or we could've gone down 1 times 0.5 times 0.2
— 或者我们直接用 1 x 0.5 x 0.2 x 10 的 -7 次方
times 10 to the negative 7th which is equal to times to negative 8.
等于 10 的 -8 次方
&gt;&gt; It looks like these numbers could get really small.
— 看起来这些数字的确很小
&gt;&gt; Yes, in practice we should use log space to calculate these probabilities.
— 是的 实际上我们应该使用 logspace 计算这些概率
Otherwise we run out of precision in the way the OS represents numbers.
否则我们失去观测序列表示数字方式的精确性
To keep things simple, let's keep going.
为了简化 我们继续进行
&gt;&gt; Okay, next at t equal to 3, our expected values from
— 好 接下来 t 等于 3 我们对状态 1 的期望值
state 1 are .8 times .6 and .2 times 10 to the negative 5.
是 0.8 x 0.6 和 0.2 x 10 的 -5 次方
It looks like we should multiply the previous result,
看来我们应该用之前的结果 0.2
.2 by our new expected values.
乘以新的期望值
&gt;&gt; Right &gt;&gt; We also have to account for
— 没错 — 我们也要解释
the path that went through state two earlier.That one will become ten to
更早进入状态 2 的路径 这个成为
the negative eight times zero point five time ten to the negative five or
10 的 -8 次方 乘以 0.5 乘以 10 的 -5 次方
ten time zero point five time ten to the four.
或者是 10 的 -7 次方乘以 0.5 乘以 10 的 -4 次方
&gt;&gt; Free state, we going to keep the path with maximum value, for
— 自由状态 我们继续走最大值的路径
state one is going to be this number.
因为状态 1 是这个数字
For state two, it's going to be this number, for
状态 2 是这个数字
state three, it'll be this number.
状态 3 是这个数字
We'll continue this process keeping track of the maximum path to get to
我们继续这个过程 跟踪最大值路径
each state at each time through the trailers.
通过跟踪结果到达每次的状态
At the end, we choose the most likely path.
最后我们选择最有可能的路径
For this trellis, it turns out to be this one.
对这个网格图 结果是这样的
The final answer for the probability of the observation given
根据模型得到的最后观测概率
our model is about 0.00035.
约为 0.00035
We can then compare this probability to the corresponding result from
然后我们对比这个概率
the trellis for we.
和 we 网格图中对应的结果